James Robert France

Summary

Certified Salesforce developer with six years of experience developing in Salesforce, and 18 years of experience in IT overall. Largely self-taught in Salesforce, having completed over 180 badges on the Trailhead site. During my career I have developed applications and performed maintenance on systems encompassing a variety of technologies.

Core Competencies

- Apex Program Development
- Declarative Development
- System Analysis
- Project Scoping
- Quality Assurance Testing

- Agile Methodology
- Specifications Documentation
- Data Analysis
- Project Administration
- Document Management

Employment History

Arlanis Reply UK, London From November 2021 to August 2023

I was employed as a Salesforce developer for Arlanis Reply UK, a subsidiary of Reply. The company was formerly known as Forcology and performs consulting work and new Salesforce developments for external clients. The client base is mostly involved in the motor industry.

- Performing a support role for several clients on their Salesforce orgs, resolving tickets which are raised by the clients.
- Performing monthly sprints and deployments of changes by other developers for a leading manufacturer of industrial equipment.
- I created a community in Experience Cloud for a major German motor manufacturer which allowed company drivers to book a pool car.
- Performing regular data loads for a client.
- Working with document templates created in S-Docs with S-Sign functionality.
- Creating Conga templates.
- Creating macros to generate emails from classic email templates.

Technologies:

Salesforce Sales Cloud, Salesforce Experience Cloud, Apex, SOQL, Salesforce CLI, Visual Studio Code, Git, Azure DevOps, S-Docs, S-Sign

Alscient, Leeds From June 2021 to October 2021

I was employed as a Salesforce developer, performing consulting work and Salesforce developments for external clients.

- Coding rest API web service callouts to other systems such as Ceedbox, Cx and Stripe.
- I created a Visualforce page that used a wrapper class to display charts of patient information alongside text blocks for a therapist to enter notes.
- I worked on a system change for a client to select the correct price book for a client depending on pricing category and country.
- Assisting clients with tuition on user security, reports and dashboards.

Technologies:

Salesforce Sales Cloud, Salesforce Experience Cloud, Apex, Visualforce, SOQL, DML, Salesforce CLI, Visual Studio Code, Git, JIRA, Slack, AWS

Zurich Insurance Group, Swindon From December 2019 to June 2021

I was employed as a Salesforce developer in the company's DevOps team where I supported users both within Zurich UK and in companies partnered with Zurich. The orgs that I worked on were UK General Insurance, UK Life, and Zurich Community Trust.

- Discussing system functionality and possible new features with senior stakeholders in the business in weekly meetings.
- Supporting users who raise system incidents.
- Performing small changes to the Salesforce orgs in an Agile environment.
- Adding components to Lightning Page Layouts.
- Creating new Visualforce pages with Apex controllers and test classes.
- Declarative developments and process automation.

Technologies:

Salesforce, Apex, Visualforce, Aura Components, SOQL, DML, Salesforce CLI, Visual Studio Code, JIRA, Service Now

thryve, Johannesburg, South Africa From August 2017 to November 2019

As a Salesforce developer I supported clients who used the Riskonnect risk management system and other software that thryve created in-house.

- Creating new Visualforce pages with Apex controllers and test classes.
- Declarative developments and process automation.
- Creating custom reports using Visualforce pages with Excel output.
- Integrating data which was exported from other systems.
- Change control and version control using Salesforce CLI and GitHub.
- Metadata migrations from one organisation to another using Eclipse.

Projects:

- I worked on a project to prepare a client for the new financial year's client data collection. This project involved combining several objects into one and rolling over values to a previous year lookup record.
- I helped move one company's division to a new Salesforce organisation. Metadata was moved using Eclipse, and all data was downloaded to Excel and uploaded to Salesforce using Data Import Wizard and Data Loader.
- I worked with a colleague to set up a new client with Riskonnect's Renewal Data Collection tool. All configurations were set up as per the client's requirements, and all the required survey questions were imported using metadata configurations set up using XML.

Technologies:

Salesforce, Riskonnect, Apex, Visualforce, Aura Components, HTML, JQuery, Javascript, SOQL, DML, Salesforce CLI, GitHub, Eclipse

Alliance Business Solutions / Bytes Universal Systems, Midrand, South Africa From November 2011 to August 2017

Alliance Business Solutions was an Oracle partner which was integrated into Bytes Universal Systems. I was employed in a variety of roles as the business required.

- Performed Salesforce developments including Visualforce pages to embed in page layouts, reports, dashboards and communities.
- Created JD Edwards and BI Publisher reports
- Created Business Services interfaces written in Java, which connected JD Edwards with external systems.
- Administered major system integration projects using the OUM methodology, and managed project documentation.
- Performed JD Edwards CNC duties for various clients: Performing daily checks on servers, starting and stopping services, setting up job schedules, monitoring scheduled jobs, building and deploying PY and PD packages, and user security

Technologies:

Salesforce, SQL, JD Edwards, BI Publisher, Java, E-Business Suite, Primavera, WebMethods, Unix

Katide Information & Management Systems, Halfway House, South Africa From August 2011 to November 2011

As an Oracle E-Business Suite applications consultant I was part of the project team at Bateman which was converting the R12 Oracle system to B12.

Technologies:

Oracle/E-Business Suite, SQL

Education

- Completed a course in Lightning Web Components in 2021.
- Completed a PEAK II project management course while on a project for Lafarge South Africa.
- Obtained C++, Java, SQL, HTML, XML and JSP programming certificates at the Computer Training Institute in Johannesburg.
- Obtained a diploma in COBOL programming at the Luso Computer Institute in Johannesburg. The course consisted of programming, program design and Concepts of Data Processing. Officially certified by the Information Technology Users' Council, Johannesburg.

Certifications

- Salesforce Platform Developer 1
- Salesforce Certified Associate
- Oracle Associate Java Programmer
- Information Technology Users' Council COBOL Programmer

Memberships

British MENSA